hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft we're
getting pretty close and comfortable and
if you don't know where i am maybe you
can guess from the background but i have
been in mumbo's witch farm for about 48
hours two days straight afk i've been so
lucky nobody's kicked me i haven't
crashed nothing i've just been afk here
for two whole days but now
it's time for me to emerge from this
hole and see how we've done for those of
you that don't know about mumbo's witch
farm basically they all spawn in here
which is where witch hut would be
the floors then shift
and then it releases the witches down
into here and then all the items are
carried along and then they get
deposited in here now i've been here for
48 hours
and it seems like it's done pretty well
now what we're really after is all of
this redstone dust
there was two shulker boxes in here so
48 hours has only given me like eight
shulker boxes that should be enough
redstone for the sahara project and now
we just have to deliver it back to the
sahara hq of course i won't actually be
using any of this redstone but i thought
i would be useful in collecting it let's
head back over i didn't make this
someone's clearly gone this is where the
fountain's supposed to be
definitely a table i literally don't
understand is there something on top
nope there's
nothing
nothing here well we know this wasn't
iskal because there's diorite been used
and we know that he wouldn't do that
this is really weird
really weird either way we should
deliver all of this redstone as we
promised one two three eight nine
ten but i think my two day long afk
session is finally over and i think we
can actually get cracking on building
the front of this
now i am honestly not sure what to make
here
it's a it's quite a big area i obviously
need to have this kind of style
but i'm sure i can come up with
something so let's go into a time lapse
and see what we can come up with i think
the first thing that we're going to do
in this time lapse is remove this table
i'm not quite sure what it was to this
day
but i think it's best that we just crack
on because what i wanted to put here was
originally a fountain but then i thought
sahara architect desert so i put a giant
a over a little bit of sand and then i
tried to work out the best way to
decorate it and that didn't go too well
as you can see but i want to talk to you
about something else while this time
lapse is rolling as many of you know
before youtube i founded a server called
wincraft which is an mmorpg
and it's still going to this day and i
still work on it with my friend salted
and a bunch of other people in this
massive team it's a really really big
project and the server's still rolling
to this date and we've actually done a
pretty big update so and i don't do this
very often i thought i would put this
new trailer
in today's video to show you so
if you don't want to view it feel free
to just skip those two minutes but if
you've got two minutes to spare i would
love for you to take a look at it anyway
that's a bit later on but let's get back
into the sahara as you can see this is
very much a silicon valley style shop
front so it's kind of like halfway
between an apple store and an ikea i
guess but we're trying to make it as
unique as possible i totally did this on
the fly i had no idea what i was doing
but i think it came out pretty pretty
well
anyway that's about all for this time
lapse let's get back into the game
it took quite a while to make this but i
think that it actually looks really good
it's very very unfinished let's do a
little quick reveal
and there it is the front of sahara has
been made this should then give mumbo
and iskall the space that they need for
the interface so you come in here the
lobby will be all up in here it's quite
a big space to fill and the interface
will be somewhere around here maybe a
few blocks back but essentially i don't
want you to go into the shop and then
have to look for it because all of these
shops the ones that are truly successful
you go in you take the stuff and you buy
and you get out you don't have to faff
around too much that's why i'm not a
massive fan of the wool shop because
you've got to go swimming all the way
around the rainbow but with this you
come in you make your order and off it
goes and of course we'll make some
staircases to get up into the main parts
and when we take a bigger look at
everything you can see how massive this
project is even if none of the redstone
started my job is very nearly finished
oh my goodness this is a such an
enormous project but i think there's
nothing like this in minecraft so far
and there's certainly nothing like this
on the hermitcraft server i'm very
excited for how this is going but as i
said in the time lapse i actually wanted
to show you guys a trailer for the new
update on the server that i co-own with
my friend salted and he has made this
trailer for the new update and if i
could just spare two minutes of your
time to check it out and see if you like
it
that would be great so let's roll the
trailer
[Music]
yep so that is wincraft my server that
i've been running and owning with my
friend salted for about six years which
is absolutely crazy if you like it there
is a link in the description and there
is a link to the ip address but as you
know just for full disclosure this is a
server that i own and i do benefit from
it but anyway let's continue on with
hermitcraft because i received a message
on discord
that the jangler has hit again i have no
idea what he's done
but apparently something has appeared
in my office
i've got my sherlock green skin on i'm
ready to solve some mysteries and to
jingle some jangles
what
i love this skin i should i add eyebrows
to more of my skins because this just
this just does everything anyway i've
messaged ren and doc or should i say
renzon and dachshund and there's cookies
everywhere to meet me in my office so
that we can have a look at what's going
on so let's head into my office shall we
[Music]
well hello boys
hello sherlock so this is our first this
is like our second meeting on this case
and how has your investigation been
going
um
well
it didn't go too well
right
now i i don't want to say i i saw this
coming but
go on what happened
well we went over to stress monster we
interrogated her
uh we
figured that her carrots weren't in fact
made out of biscuits and then she killed
me that's that's how the investigation
was told you i didn't think it was
stress
dachshund i've been murdered
we were so certain though the clues
though they weren't oh it was okay well
right so it's not stress is what you're
saying no no no
and um for future reference we're never
gonna question or ask her anything again
because whenever we come close to her
she kills us so yeah nope
not yeah
that's a good idea well as we know the
jungler has struck again so we've got a
new lead he's actually left a couple of
signs right here it says best lamp ever
which is you know i'm flattered jangler
thank you that is a snazzy lamp too bad
there's no light coming out of it though
yeah and um yeah yeah he just left the
one sign but let's have a let's have a
look
oh hey boys and dog
dog again
why because you're scary dude
i see you are on my trail sherlock oh
this is a silly game you will surely
lose as i'm putting down roots on the
server with my own shop to spread good
deeds
is this this must be some sort of
riddle
of sometimes this is a silly game you
will surely lose as i am putting down
roots on the server with my own shop to
spread good deeds
yeah i mean if i could raise my eyebrow
i would right now i mean i'm i am always
yes
well i didn't see a new shop out there
anywhere no i haven't maybe we should go
and have a little look around all right
he did leave another side leave another
sign
how do you think you are i think he
means who
wait a minute
how
what i think he means who
peter pan why yes i do thank you
right let's have a quick scout over the
shopping district to see if there's a
new shop it might be fairly small what
is going on guys there's all of these
shops have been taken by
concord yeah yeah
there's some sort of corporate espionage
happening
how have they taken the time
yeah yeah yeah okay sorry yeah i'm
getting distracted
[Music]
over here i'm over here at the stock
exchange just that fancy new sahara
should we check the ball maybe yeah
let's go have a look in the mall
no
dirty deeds is that is that part of it
he said no he said uh with my own shop
to spread good deeds sherlock docks and
i've made a discovery i think
uh the iron shop
flames up there i've never seen those
flames up there before ah that looks
like yeah that might be what we're
looking for
you guys have ender pearls i have to fly
haha
right
this is a shop jangler shop oh right
yeah okay
there's nothing in here that says that
it would be in the mall though so i it
took us a good look it took us a while
to find this to be fair yeah there's
nothing in here apart from yeah so he's
laid down a shop let's go and have a
look inside shall we
i don't trust it
[Music]
oh my god look at this
whoa
what oh my god it's an oven it's an oven
with cookies in well this is amazing all
right should we let's let's go and read
it let's stop admiring the work and
let's go and read it shall we all right
all right um would you like the jungler
to prank someone order now
place an order here for a bad deed place
an order here for a good deed
oh
so would you like the jangler to prank
someone well oh yes
yeah of course man i mean his pranks are
glorious you know come to my base and
build me a cookie factory there's
clearly some redstone going on here as
well by the way it's like very much not
hidden
oh oh yes very much not hidden anyway
let's go and have a look shall we what
that's a well spotted clue over there um
i'm gonna go for
did i go for a bad deed the jungler only
does good oh silly um i've fallen into a
pit
[Laughter]
no okay all right
hello
boys
please
i'm sorry dog
um no i'm not my bad dude my bad
there's two books in there i
i went to get the second book
why were you still standing there
oh my goodness i i okay so i opened the
bad deed
and he there's a parrot head that says
the jangler only does good deeds and
there's a couple of books in here
i'm so sorry um yeah i'll wait for you
guys to get back here
okay oh my goodness so what does the
good deed say oh the good deed oh the
good deed gave some fireworks i'll wait
for you guys to get back
i am so sorry guys
guys they're on their way back right now
so i'm gonna use this opportunity since
they've died i've got i've just had a
genius idea of just muted on discord so
they have no idea um they'll probably
freak out while i log out for a second
but watch this
i don't i don't have a door with me but
i'm gonna try and sell them a did you
die box right now
uh doc so this might be a good
opportunity to um listen to uh one of my
pitches so um it looks like you just
died and would you be interested in uh
purchasing
wait a minute man
the timer is running what are you on
about yes i'll take it there's there's
uh three stacks of diamonds
what three stacks of diamonds dude
there's a lot of stuff in here you know
you don't want to miss this bargain of
the century
dude
your stuff is gonna despawn why don't
you just buy a new new box you know
you got there's you know three stacks of
diamonds it's a bargain i'm telling you
this there's there's hours of work in
this box there's hours of work this is
the most aggressive marketing i've ever
seen like we don't have a choice you
either you either jump down there and
get your stuff or you buy one of my
boxes
[Laughter]
why would anyone buy my box
our stuff is gone
no rip yeah
no oh no it's it's floating here i'm
gonna help you knock get it
i'm gonna try i'm actually gonna kill
i'm just gonna kill these puffer fish
because i don't want to lose
oh that's a good idea why didn't we just
kill the puffer fish
right so um
the cost of all the stuff back is buying
one of these boxes so you get double the
amount of stuff
how about that
dachshund
i think we've beaten that beezled over
here
you say we want to make business with
sahara in the future and not join concur
corp you know all right okay so let's
just let's spend five minutes uh just
divvying up the stuff okay right so
who's got a spoon
mwah
flippers
and then ender pearls and ender chest
and i'm afraid that's it guys
um
so what have we lost what's the damage i
got everything i think
i
would you like to buy a did you die box
[Laughter]
so we tried the bad one um yeah so this
is what happens if you do the good one
you get you get you get loads of
fireworks oh wow that's awesome you get
a bit of firework action i can't believe
her oh we got jangled i'm gonna cover up
this hole even though there's nothing
down there anymore yeah
okay right so should we read the bad
deed books first i haven't even had a
chance
okay right uh oh it's an empty book oh
they're all
oh yeah that's the one we've already
read yep they're empty books great well
i think those are for the orders
oh yeah they're the orders oh so they're
all empty i see
i think we've now got to get one over on
the jungler
yeah i don't think we can chase him like
this because otherwise you two are gonna
actually you know we could keep going
because i need to sell more did you die
boxes
come on man i have a vendetta right now
that needs resolution okay so why don't
we try and why don't we try and set a
trap for the jungler
okay
and see if
we can catch him in the act or something
no that's a that's a really good idea so
why don't we
play
why don't no why don't we do this why
don't we set up a shop
and sell all of these cookies and we
place an order for him to go and buy all
of the cookies all right scooby-doo and
doc let's
build a shop that sells cookies actually
we actually need cookies maybe we should
right ren you you what are you doing ren
um that's scooby
scooby what are you doing
uh hello hi
right your job is to go and get as many
cookies from that flying cookie as
possible and we're gonna sell the
jangler his own cookies
okay okay good that sounds great all
right and we're gonna make
we're gonna make the shop right here
because this is the most central point
in the shopping district and it's going
to get seen sound good
good plan sherlock i have to compliment
you this
is an ugly cookie it's a really ugly
cookie
it's i thought it was a pokemon what
it's yeah it's got eyes a very ugly
cookie
it looks so sad it's looking good to me
it's meant to be ugly we're kind of
taking god i'm taking the mick out of
the jungler right we're we're making a
really bad cookie shop
oh
that's that's genius
this is this is the whole this is the
whole thing right we're gonna charge a
ridiculous amount of uh diamonds for
cookies we're gonna fill this chest with
batches of 16 cookies
and we're gonna sell them for a diamond
each which is ludicrous but because
we've put an order in to buy all of the
cookies at the shop we're making free
money nice i love it i love it it's a
genius idea also i have a contribution
to make to this particular project um
i've spent the majority of the day
working on it um
this this business is now owned by puffy
puffy puffy cookie ink welcomes you
all right so let me put this down one
diamond per
16. we're gonna be rich
also you know
a little bit of compensation for ren's
losses
we've got to get ren's armor back and
the thing is guys these are super rare
cookies this is a part of hermitcraft
history okay no cookies like this will
ever exist ever again in hermitcraft i
think it's a bargain and as soon as soon
as all the cookies are sold we're just
gonna take this down and then there's no
refunds
yeah
that's the old rule anyways no refunds
that's the basic
all right well the last thing that we
need to do is actually put the order in
the jungler shop and then job done and
then we wait for the jungler to fall for
the trap
so the jangler trap is now set and i've
got to continue on sahara because it's
yeah this is a massive project look at
the size of that building this building
but mumbo and isco have actually just
got on and they're going to be doing the
redstone today so i'm super motivated to
try and get this part of the building
done as quickly as possible
but there's a lot of crafting that needs
to happen and i mean a lot so i've
crafted up a stack of dispensers and all
of the redstone stuff that we're going
to be needing like we're getting all of
this stuff together
and
iskall's getting all of the concrete
ready for all the bits where the
redstone's going to be laid down this is
a enormous project but we actually need
a lot of quartz so to see this video off
i need to go on a quartz hunt
so that's it for today's video i want to
say a big big thank you if you did watch
this video all the way to the end hello
people that watch all the way to the end
you are very few so this is kind of an
exclusive you know thank you whatever
but also thank you if you did watch the
trailer it is a java edition minecraft
server wincraft and i do hope that you
check it out if you can the ip will be
in the description below now after this
i went and delivered the quartz back to
mumbo and iskall and they were already
working on the redstone for sahara and i
decided not to be very helpful so enjoy
this small clip of me being annoying and
good bye
[Music]
do
you